Finding Aid for College of Engineering (University of Michigan) records 1860-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Associate Dean's Files, 1980-1992
  - Project Files of Dan Atkins
    The two sections "Industrial Technology Institute" (ITI) and "Center for Robotics and Integrated Manufacturing" (CRIM) document the establishment of these important research facilities in the early 1980s and include proposals, correspondence, reports, and newsclippings. Information regarding the relationship between the two facilities is located in the CRIM section in the folders "Industrial Technology Institute (ITI) and CRIM." The section "Institute of Science and Technology" is not as well documented as the other two research facilities and consists of correspondence and reviews. There are two folders from Atkins' participation as a member of the 1988 "Provost Search Advisory Committee"; these are closed to researchers.
    - Experimental Research in Electronic Submission (EXPRES) Project
      - Chronological Files
        - 1986, 2 folders (Box 47)
        - 1987
          - January-June, 3 folders (Box 47)
          - July-December (includes Advisory Committee Meeting materials), 4 folders (Box 47)
        - 1988
          - January-March, 3 folders (Box 47)
          - April (includes Advisory Committee Meeting materials), 2 folders (Box 47)
          - May-October, 6 folders (Box 47)
          - November-December, 2 folders (Box 48)
        - 1989
          - January-March, 3 folders (Box 48)
      - Topical Files
        - Articles, Newsclippings, and Press Releases, 1985-1988 (Box 48)
        - Budget, 1986-1988 (Box 48)
        - Cooperative Agreement with National Science Foundation, 1986-1988 (Box 48)
        - Directory of EXPRES Participants, 1986-1988 (Box 48)
        - File Notes (reports, proposals, etc.), 1985-1987 (Box 48)
        - Personnel, 1987-1988 (Box 48)
        - Planning Documents, 1986-1987 (Box 48)
        - Proposal (re: establishment), 1986 (Box 48)
        - Subcontractors
          - ArborText, Inc., 1986-1988 (Box 48)
          - BBN Laboratories, Inc., 1986-1989 (Box 48)
        - Test Site Partners, 1986-1987 (Box 48)
        - Vendors of EXPRES, 1987 undated (Box 48)
        - Videotape (materials regarding), 1987 (Box 48)
  - H.S. Fogler
    H.S. Fogler (1 linear foot) served as Associate Dean for Instruction from 1978 to 1983. His files document diverse issues, including curriculum development, the college Co-op Program, minority recruitment, and rules regarding transfer students.
    - Atkins, D.E., 1982-1983 (Box 59)
    - Center for Research on Learning and Teaching, 1981-1983 (Box 59)
    - Co-op Program
      - Correspondence, 1980-1983 (Box 59)
      - General Motors, 1982-1983 (Box 59)
      - Grant, 1983 (Box 59)
      - Placement Interview Computerization, 1983 (Box 59)
      - Placement Office, 1981-1983 (Box 59)
      - Program Talk, 1983 (Box 59)
      - Questionnaire Responses, 1982 (Box 59)
    - Curriculum Committee, 1981-1983 (Box 59)
    - Deans' Meeting with Regents, 1982 (Box 59)
    - Department of Defense Equipment Proposal, 1982; 2 folders (Box 59)
    - Draft Document on Cooperative Education, 1981 (Box 59)
    - Duderstadt, J.J., 1981-1982 (Box 59)
    - Engineering Council, 1983 (Box 59)
    - Engineering Education, 1981-1982 (Box 59)
    - Engineering Factbook, 1982 (Box 59)
    - Faculty, 1983 (Box 59)
    - Fundraising Report by Ketchum Inc., 1982 (Box 59)
    - Grant Applications, 1983 (Box 60)
    - "Hit and Run" Committee (Transfers), 1983 (Box 60)
    - Industrial and Operations Engineering Students, 1983 (Box 60)
    - Instructional Complex-North Campus, 1982 (Box 60)
    - Intellectual Activities Surve, circa 1982 (Box 60)
    - Interactive Computing Release Time, 1982 (Box 60)
    - Materials and Metallurgical Engineering, 1982-1983 (Box 60)
    - Mathematics Department Teaching, 1982 (Box 60)
    - Mechanical Engineering and Applied Mechanics, 1982-1983 (Box 60)
    - Michigan Engineering College Liaison Meeting, 1982 (Box 60)
    - Minorities-Correspondence, 1978-1983 (Box 60)
    - Minorities-General Information, 1981-1982 (Box 60)
    - National Advisory Committee, 1983 (Box 60)
    - Nominations for President/Director of Industrial Technology Institute, 1982-1983 (Box 84)
    - North Campus Move, 1982 (Box 60)
    - Open-Ended Problem Solving, 1983 (Box 60)
    - Quackenbush, L.J., 1981-1983 (Box 60)
    - Records Office, 1983 (Box 60)
    - Recruiting, 1982-1983 (Box 60)
    - Research Incentive Distribution, 1982-1983 (Box 60)
    - Scheduling, 1981 (Box 60)
    - Scholastic Standing Committee, 1982-1983 (Box 60)
    - Senior Research Fellowship Program, 1981-1982 (Box 60)
    - Staff Responsibilities, 1982-1983 (Box 84)
    - Student Societies, 1981 (Box 60)
    - Summer Appointments, 1981-1982 (Box 60)
    - Teaching Awards, 1982 (Box 60)
    - Teaching Brochure, 1983 (Box 60)
    - Technical Communication Program Status and Future Direction, 1983 (Box 60)
    - Transfer Student Comparison Database, circa 1981-1983 (Box 60)
    - Vest, C.M., 1981-1983 (Box 60)
    - Video Technology in Education, 1982 (Box 60)
  - M.J. Sinnott
    The M.J. Sinnott subseries (1 linear foot) runs from 1967 to 1984; it contains some files created by Sinnott's predecessor as Associate Dean, W.H. Farris. The subseries documents administrative concerns such as staffing, grant applications, accreditation and space allocation. The "Macnee Willow Run Report" folders [box 60] document deliberations surrounding the appropriate use of Willow Run Laboratories, which was a controversial issue during the late 1960s.
    - Academic Calendar, 1974-1978 (Box 60)
    - Classified Research, 1967-1973 (Box 60)
    - Engineering-Mathematics-Statistics Committee, 1977-1981 (Box 60)
    - Engineers' Council for Professional Development (ECPD), 1968-1975 (Box 60)
    - Fluid Mechanics, 1975 (Box 60)
    - Ford-N.S.F. Proposal, 1972-1978 (Box 60)
    - Industry Committee, 1967-1973 (Box 60)
    - Instructional Television, 1973-1984 (Box 60)
    - Library Search Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 60)
    - Macnee Willow Run Report, 1969-1971; 2 folders (Box 60)
    - McAdam, Ken (space allocation), 1973-1976 (Box 61)
    - National Science Foundation, 1973-1978; 2 folders (Box 61)
    - New Faculty Requests, 1981 (Box 61)
    - North Central Accreditation, 1977 (Box 61)
    - Office of Academic Planning and Development, 1974-1978 (Box 61)
    - Primary Research Staff, 1973 (Box 61)
    - Promotions, 1973-1981 (Box 84)
    - Research Advisory Council, 1978-1981 (Box 61)
    - Retirements, 1972-1975 (Box 61)
    - Sabbatical Reports, 1972-1974 (Box 61)
    - Sea Grant Proposal, 1969-1978; 1 volumes; 1 folders (Box 61)
    - Simulation Center, 1968-1972 (Box 61)
    - Tenure, 1973-1980 (Box 61)
  - Anne Monterio
    - Administrative Records
      - Proposed Changes to Undergraduate Curriculum, April 1996 (Box 96)
    - Facility Services
      - Construction of New Engineering Building, January 1994-March 1995 (Box 96)
      - Construction of New Engineering Building, undated (Box 96)
    - Faculty Records
      - Agendas and Notes from Faculty Meetings, 1992-2001 (Box 96)
    - International Programs
      - France, 1991-1992 (Box 96)
      - Germany, 1991-1992 (Box 96)
      - Po, 1998 (Box 96)
      - Russia, 1990-1997 (Box 96)
      - South Africa, 1988-1994 (Box 96)
    - Topical Files
      - Black Action Movement (BAM) Documentation, 1970-1982 (Box 96)
      - Bolden, Jr., Colonel Charles F. Campus Visit, 1992 (Box 96)
      - Center for Advancement of Science, Engineering, and Technology (CASET), 1987-1988 (Box 96)
      - Detroit Area Pre-College Engineering Program (DAPCEP), Supplementary Proposal, 1977-1979 (Box 96)
      - DAPCEP Article, 1995 (Box 96)
      - DAPCEP Presentation, December 17, 1997 (Box 96)
      - Journey Career Guidance Series Informational Packet [GEM Program], 1988 (Box 96)
      - Midwest Program for Minorities in Engineering, 1974 (Box 97)
      - Minority Engineering Program Office (MEPO) Fact Sheets, 1987-1996 (Box 97)
      - MEPO General, 1975-1991 (Box 97)
      - MEPO Proposal, 1975 (Box 97)
      - Minority Summer Research Program, 1976 (Box 97)
      - Miscellaneous Records Regarding Minority Presence on Michigan' s Campus, 1970-1989 (Box 97)
      - National Advisory Committee Workshop, September 15, 1989 (Box 97)
      - National Consortium for Graduate Degrees for Minorities in Engineering and Science (GEM Program) (Box 97)
      - Office of Minority Affairs, 1991-1992 (Box 97)
      - Plan for the Creation of a Supportive Environment for Black Students, 1970 (Box 97)
      - "Professionals in Training" Program, 1981 (Box 97)
      - Program in Engineering Teaching for Minority Students (PETMS), 1977-1979 (Box 97)
      - "Summary Findings from a Preliminary Study of Black Student Adjustment, Achievement and Aspirations at the University of Michigan (Ann Arbor) Winter, 1980", 1981 (Box 97)
    - Videotapes
      - Colonel Bolden and Journey Promo, VHS (Box 97)
      - Journey Promo, Charlie Bolden Segment, Phil Hill Segment, 1988; U-matic (Box 97)
      - Revised Journey Promo, 1988; U-matic (Box 97)
      - Journey Episode 1 Experiencing Decision Making, VHS (Box 97)
      - Journey PBS Special, 1992; 14 minute excerpt tape, VHS (Box 97)
      - Journey One-Hour PBS Special, May 15, 1992; VHS (Box 97)
      - "Lighting the Spark" DAPCEP/Archer, 1997; VHS (Box 97)
      - "Steps to Follow to Graduate School,", 1984; U-matic (Box 97)
      - "Why Graduate School?,", 1984; U-matic (Box 97)
- Committee Records, 1887-1994
  The Committee Records series (7.8 linear feet) dates from 1887 to 1984 and contains nearly complete runs of the minutes of the Executive Committee from its inception in 1936 to 1984 and of the Standing Committee for the period 1887 to 1983. The Standing Committee, composed of the dean, assistant dean, and chairmen of the various departments, was created in 1906 to replace an earlier advisory committee that consisted of five faculty members and the dean as an ex-officio member. The Standing Committee was responsible for approving appointments, buildings and rooms, repairs to buildings, and apparatus and equipment. The Standing Committee series includes minutes of meetings and correspondence that give a broad view of issues that were of interest to the students and faculty in engineering. The early minutes, for example, express the concern that engineering education was too technical and did not provide a broad liberal education.
  The Executive Committee was formed in 1936 as part of the Standing Committee. Its duties were to investigate and formulate educational and research policy and to consider matters of budget, promotions and appointments, and plant extension. The minutes of the Executive Committee relate to student petitions about requirements, faculty appointments, sabbaticals and sick leaves, travel expenses, building expansion, and curriculum development. Although fairly routine in the later years, the resolutions regarding research contracts with private companies included in the early minutes provide an overview of the research projects faculty members engaged in and of the relations between industry and the College of Engineering. A subject and name index for the period 1936 to 1946 provides easy access to the Executive Committee minutes. Also included in this series is a 1926 report on entering students by the Committee on the Study of Engineering Education and a 1930 file of the Committee on Engineering
  Also included are minutes of the Administrative, Curriculum and Standing Committees. The Committee on Discipline minutes (1913-1923) provide an unusual record of some engineering students' infractions, academic and otherwise, and of punishments meted out by the committee. Several of the Dean's Topical Files include files on various committees.
  - Executive Committee
    - Index, 1936-1946 (Box 27)
    - Minutes, 1936-1984
      - March 10, 1936-1957, 27 folders (Box 27)
      - 1958-1977, 18 folders (Box 28)
      - 1980-July 1984, 3 volumes; 13 folders (Box 86)
      - September-November 1984, 11 folders (Box 87)
    - Members, 1951-1971 (Box 28)
    - Guidelines, 1976-1980 (Box 75)
  - Standing Committee
    - 1887-1919, 17 folders (Box 28)
    - 1920-1961, 24 folders (Box 29)
    - 1962-1970, 9 folders (Box 30)
    - 1970-1977, 2 folders (Box 75)
    - 1978-1983, 2 volumes (Box 76)
    - Course Revision, 1919 (Box 30)
    - Curriculum Development, 1911-1925; 4 folders (Box 30)
  - Curriculum Committee
    - 1973-1974 (Box 73)
    - 1974-1978, 9 volumes (Box 74)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 75)
  - Special Committees
    - General Committee on the Study of Engineering Education: Report on Entering Students, 1926 (Box 30)
    - Committee on Engineering Chemistry, 1930 (Box 30)
    - Administrative Committee, 1946-1982; 5 volumes; 3 folders
      - 1946-1971 (Box 75)
      - 1972-1976 (Box 86)
      - 1976-1978 (Box 86)
      - 1978-1980 (Box 86)
      - 1980-1982, 2 folders (Box 86)
    - Chair's Advisory Committee, 1992-1994; 46 folders (Box 75)
    - Discipline, Committee on, 1913-1923; 3 folders (Box 86)
    - Scholastic Standing, 1959-1984; 5 volumes; 1 folders
      - 1959 (Box 87)
        [SR RESTRICTED until Jan. 1, 2024 ]
      - 1960-1970 (Box 87)
        [SR RESTRICTED until Jan. 1, 2045 ]
      - 1981 (Box 87)
        [SR RESTRICTED until Jan. 1, 2056 ]
      - 1981-1982 (Box 87)
        [SR RESTRICTED until Jan. 1, 2057 ]
      - 1982-1983 (Box 87)
        [SR RESTRICTED until Jan. 1, 2058 ]
      - 1983-1984 (Box 87)
        [SR RESTRICTED until Jan. 1, 2059 ]
    - Staff, 1965-1983; 3 volumes (Box 75)
  - Strategic Resource Planning Group, 1991-1994
    - Academic Support, 1993 (Box 88)
    - Enrollment Planning and Management, 1993-1994 (Box 88)
    - General Fund Support for Research, 1993 (Box 88)
    - Futures Task Team, 1993-1994
      - September-December 1993 (Box 88)
      - January-February 1994 (Box 88)
      - April-May 1994 (Box 88)
    - Meetings, 1991-1994
      - April 1991 (Box 88)
      - July 1991 (Box 88)
      - March 1993 (Box 88)
      - June 1993 (Box 88)
      - September 1993 (Box 88)
      - December 1993 (Box 88)
      - April 1994 (Box 88)
    - Strategic Resource Planning Team
      - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 88)
      - Minutes (Box 88)
    - Supplemental Salary Program (Box 88)
- Faculty Records, 1873-1986
  The Faculty Records series (5.5 linear feet) covers the years 1873 to 1986 and consists primarily of minutes of faculty meetings and faculty biographies; other materials include photographic rosters of the engineering faculty and a small amount of correspondence, reports, and miscellaneous material. Included in the reports is an undated report written by Professor DeVolson Wood, who taught at the University from 1857 to 1872, regarding needs of the Department of Engineering for an additional professor and appropriation requests and research reports written by faculty members in the 1870's and 1880's.
  Minutes of faculty meetings span the period 1895 to 1968 and deal for the most part with curriculum development and student requirements. Biographies of faculty members consist of questionnaires filled out by professors in the 1950's and 1960's in which they describe their educational background, teaching and industrial experience, consulting work and other activities outside of academic appointments, professional society membership, and related subjects. These biographical sketches provide substantial information on the subject of outside research by faculty members.
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes
    - Index to minutes
      - Vol. 1 (Box 30)
      - Vol. 2 (Box 31)
    - Minutes
      - 1895-1901, 2 sets in 4 volumes (Box 31)
      - September 1904-June 1924, 6 volumes (Box 31)
      - October 1924-May 1959, 7 volumes (Box 32)
      - October 1959-April 1967, 3 volumes (Box 33)
      - September 1967-December 1968 (Box 33)
  - Biographies of Faculty Members
    - 1954, 1964-1965/66; 8 folders (Box 33)
    - 1965/66, 1968/69-1969/70; 15 folders (Box 34)
    - 1969/70, 3 folders (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Correspondence, 1919-1954 (scattered) (Box 35)
    - Miscellaneous, 1934; 1950; 1954 (Box 35)
    - Photographic Roster, 1960-1979; 7 folders (Box 35)
    - Reports
      - 1873, 1880-1881; undated (Box 35)
      - 1911 (Box 35)
      - 1916-1917 (Box 35)
      - The University College, 1927-28, 1 volumes (Box 35)
      - Mechanical Engineering Curriculum, 1930 (Box 35)
      - Mining Instruction, 1936 (Box 35)
  - Individual Files
    - 1890-1990
      - Abott, Herbert L., 1908 (Box 91)
      - Adams, Edward L., 1910-1928 (Box 91)
      - Anderson, Henry C., 1899-1939 (Box 91)
      - Airey, John, 1919-1923 (Box 91)
      - Albaladejo, Jose M., 1920-1921 (Box 91)
      - Allen, John R., 1910-1921 (Box 91)
      - Alt, Glenn L., 1937; 1965 (Box 91)
      - Allen, Wyeth, 1963-1974 (Box 91)
      - Alvord, Hertbert, 1961-1963 (Box 91)
      - Armstrong, John M., 1988 (Box 91)
      - Ash, Percy, 1909-1913 (Box 91)
      - Attwood, S.S. (Box 91)
      - Baier, Louis A., 1936-1971 (Box 91)
      - Bailey, Benjamin F., 1907-1954 (Box 91)
      - Baker, Edwin M., 1943 (Box 91)
      - Begeman, Myron, 1922 (Box 91)
      - Benford, Harry, 1948-1983 (Box 91)
      - Berg, Glen V., 1965-1984 (Box 91)
      - Berry, Ralph, 1958-1984 (Box 91)
      - Binder, Kurt, 1953-1987 (Box 91)
      - Black, Herbert, 1956-1971 (Box 91)
      - Balzhiser, Richard E., 1969-1971 (Box 91)
      - Bleekman, George, 1929-1972 (Box 91)
      - Bolt, Jay, 1954-1982 (Box 91)
      - Borchardt, Jack A., 1957-1984 (Box 91)
      - Boston, Orlan W., 1942-1988 (Box 91)
      - Bouchard, Harry, 1927-1953 (Box 91)
      - Boyce, Ernest, 1944-1986 (Box 91)
      - Boyd, Joseph, 1961-1981 (Box 91)
      - Bragg, Edward, 1944-1960 (Box 91)
      - Brater, Ernest, 1952-1982 (Box 91)
      - Brier, John C., 1944-1959 (Box 91)
      - Brodie, Hugh, 1909-1921 (Box 91)
      - Brown, George, 1954-1961 (Box 91)
      - Brown, Richard K., 1950-1987 (Box 91)
      - Brownell, Lloyd, 1955-1975 (Box 91)
      - Bukovsky, Paul, 1936-1943 (Box 91)
      - Bull, Hempstead S., 1945-1967 (Box 91)
      - Burklund, Edwin, 1945-1964 (Box 91)
      - Bursley, Joseph A., 1914-1920 (Box 91)
      - Busby, Hibbard, 1925-1926 (Box 91)
      - Butts, William H., 1920-1922 (Box 91)
      - Caddell, Robert, 1968-1988 (Box 91)
      - Calhoon, Floyd N., 1960-1972 (Box 91)
      - Cannon, Joseph, 1953-1963 (Box 91)
      - Carey, Clifton, 1929-1990 (Box 91)
      - Carroll, Ray, 1979 (Box 91)
      - Chapman, Sydney, 1958-1962 (Box 91)
      - Cissel, James, 1919-1949 (Box 91)
      - Clark, Albert, 1960 (Box 91)
      - Clark, John A., 1972-1988 (Box 91)
      - Cleveland, Donald, 1965-1981 (Box 91)
      - Cole, Robert C., 1937-1966 (Box 91)
      - Colwell, Lester, 1937-1984 (Box 91)
      - Cooley, Mortimer Elwyn, 1910-1971 (Box 91)
      - Cox, John C., 1915-1918 (Box 91)
      - Crawford, Ivan C., 1940-1945 (Box 91)
      - Davis, Joseph, 1909-1925 (Box 91)
      - Decker, Arthur, 1914-1946 (Box 91)
      - Evaldson, Rune, 1953 (Box 91)
      - Forbes, Arthur, 1982 (Box 91)
      - Goetz, Robert, 1987 (Box 91)
      - Goode, Harry S., 1960 (Box 91)
      - Hammitt, Frederick, 1957-1971 (Box 91)
      - Harris, Robert, 1969-1986 (Box 91)
      - Katz, Donald, 1948-1979; 3 folders (Box 91)
      - King, John., 1959-1988 (Box 92)
      - Kohl, John C., 1965-1970 (Box 92)
      - Lake, Richard, 1973 (Box 92)
      - Laitone, Jonathan, 1981 (Box 92)
      - Lay, Walter, 1934-1969 (Box 92)
      - Leach, Chester, 1990 (Box 92)
      - Lisher, Edward J., 1967-1984 (Box 92)
      - Leslie, Eugene H., 1928-1976 (Box 92)
      - Lipson, Charles, 1953-1976 (Box 92)
      - Liu, Vi-Cheng, 1950; 1988 (Box 92)
      - Lloyd, Harold, 1912-1959 (Box 92)
      - Love, Clyde E., 1905-1960 (Box 92)
      - Lovell, Alfred H., 1937 (Box 92)
      - Lorch, Emil, 1913-1914 (Box 92)
      - Martin, Edward, 1956-1985 (Box 92)
      - Martin, Robert, 1973-1986 (Box 92)
      - McMullen, Charles, 1960-1986 (Box 92)
      - Moore, Arthur, 1960-1990; 2 folders (Box 92)
      - Osborn, Richard K., 1957-1971 (Box 92)
      - Patterson, Dean George, circa 1930 (Box 92)
      - Phillips, Richard L., 1960-1980 (Box 92)
      - Quackenbush, Le, 1957-1986 (Box 92)
      - Ragone, David, 1957-1972 (Box 92)
      - Richard, Frank, 1961-1983 (Box 92)
      - Root, William L, 1961-1986 (Box 92)
      - Rumman, Wadi G., 1952-1986 (Box 92)
      - Sadler, Herbert, 1935-1960 (Box 92)
        (and Walter Sadler)
      - Scheske, Claire L., 1976-1987 (Box 92)
      - Scott, Norman, 1951-1978 (Box 92)
      - Senseman, W.M., circa 1964 (Box 92)
      - Shafter, Edward, 1954-1978 (Box 92)
      - Sherlock, R.H., circa 1957 (Box 92)
      - Sherman, Pauline, 1956-1986 (Box 92)
      - Sherzer, Allen F., circa 1936 (Box 92)
      - Stalker, Edward A., 1927-1937 (Box 92)
      - Stanton, Stephen, circa 1982 (Box 92)
      - Steinbacher, Franz R., 1944-1945 (Box 92)
      - Stinton, Roy, 1940-1945 (Box 92)
      - Tai, Chen-To., 1963-1982 (Box 92)
      - Van Vlack, Lawrence, 1954-1988 (Box 92)
      - Van Wylen, Gordon J., 1965-1972 (Box 92)
      - Vest, Charles M., circa 1988 (Box 92)
      - Weeks, Robert, circa 1986 (Box 92)
      - Wilson, Richard, 1959-1985 (Box 92)
      - Yeh, Chai, 1956-1965 (Box 92)
      - Yih, Cia-Shum, 1988 (Box 92)
      - Wilson, Richard, 1955-1986 (Box 92)
      - Ziwet, A., 1920-1923 (Box 92)
  - General Faculty Clipping File
    - A-G (Box 92)
    - H-L (Box 92)
    - M (Box 92)
    - N-R (Box 92)
    - S-T (Box 92)
    - U-Z (Box 92)
- Student and Alumni Records, 1895-1991
  The Student and Alumni Records series (6.75 linear feet) consists of a roster of admissions to the Engineering program from 1895 to 1922; a statement of requirements for admission in 1912; newsletters, directories, and miscellaneous items of alumni; lists of Mechanical Engineering graduates in the 1930's; and minutes of the annual meeting of the Class Officers Council of the Alumni Association for March 1943. The Alumni subseries contains an eighteen volume set of responses to questionnaires which were sent to College alumni in 1973. The alumni gave their opinions about the pertinence of College curricula and programs to their careers, and also responded to questions about counseling and specific departments. Alumni also contains a nearly complete set of reunion records for the class of 1904E, with correspondence and Annual Reports that provide a unique picture of class members' lives over the course of more than 60 years. Photographs of 1904E reunions are stored in box 82.
  The Students subseries includes records of student life dating from 1902 to 1991. Some items of interest in the subseries are course evaluations from the 1980s; a file on the development of the College Honor System; and a "Camp Davis Diary", kept by a student during the annual summer surveying camp in 1915.
  - General
    - Admissions, 1895-1904; 1 volumes (Box 35)
    - Admissions, 1905-1922 (Box 37)
    - Admission Requirements, 1912 (Box 35)
    - Alumni, 1914-1971 (scattered) (Box 35)
    - Alumni Association, Class Officers Council, 1943 (Box 35)
    - Mechanical Engineering Graduates, 1930-1939 (Box 35)
  - Alumni
    - Alumni Questionnaires, 1973-1974; 18 volumes
      - Volumes 1-2: Career Comments (Box 76)
      - Volumes 3-8: Curricular Comments (Box 76)
      - Volume 9: Comments on Co-op and Industry Exchange Programs (Box 76)
      - Volume 10: Comments on Counseling (Box 76)
      - Volumes 11-14: Departments (Box 77)
      - Volume 15: Undergraduate and Graduate Programs (Box 77)
      - Volumes 16-18: General Comments (Box 77)
    - Class of 1904
      - Annual Reports, 1944-1970 (Box 77)